Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/nela-richardson-59813613 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Macroeconomics
Financial Modeling
Machine Learning

Certifications

Series 7 & 66

Publications

"Rebuilding the Housing Finance System after the Boom and Bust in Nonprime Mortgage Lending" Chapter 1 in Moving Forward: The Future of Consumer Credit and Mortgage Finance

Understanding the Boom and Bust of Nonprime Mortgage Lending

Nela Richardson

Principal, Investment Strategy at Edward Jones New York City Metropolitan Area

Summary

Experienced financial economist specializing in capital markets, housing economics and monetary policy. Proven manager and expert in media relations and brand building using advanced data science techniques and analysis. Experienced in the development and management of data science projects, personnel and research, as well as machine learning, econometrics and mathematical modeling applied to finance and consumer behavior.

Experience

Edward Jones
2 years 3 months

Principal, Investment Strategist January 2020 - Present (9 months)

Investment Strategist
July 2018 - Present (2 years 3 months)

Redfin

Chief Economist
May 2014 - June 2018 (4 years 2 months)

Bloomberg LP Senior Economist April 2011 - May 2014 (3 years 2 months)

John Hopkins University
Adjunct Professor of Finance, Carey Business School
January 2011 - August 2011 (8 months)
Baltimore, MD

Commodity Futures Trading Commission Research Economist June 2009 - April 2011 (1 year 11 months)

Page 1 of 2

Harvard University's Joint Center for Housing Studies Researcher 2008 - August 2009 (1 year)

Freddie Mac Senior Economist June 2005 - August 2008 (3 years 3 months)

Education

University of Maryland PhD, Economics

University of Pennsylvania MA, Economics

Indiana University Bloomington
BA, Philosophy, Mathematics and Economics